

# VAN TABBERT

MOBILE AND WEB DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

Full stack web and mobile application developer with experience using modern JavaScript libraries and cloud integration. Analytical problem solver with the ability to quickly learn new technologies and languages. Skilled multitasker comfortable working within a team and independently. Enthusiastic mentor motivated to guide other developers to their full potential.

## **CONTACT ME**

**t**: (817) 908-7911

e: van.tabbert@gmail.com

w: www.vannya.me

facebook.com/vannienicole

github.com/vannya

in linkedIn.com/in/vannya

<u>twitter.com/vannyalock</u>

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Strong:** ReactJS, React Native, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ES6, Redux, React Router V4, Reach Router, Node.js, Express, Sass, Wordpress, Git/Version Control, Photoshop, InDesign.

**Knowledgable:** Electron, GraphQL, NoSQL, SQL, Webpack, Android, php, Java, C++, Sketch, Illustrator, Azure, Azure functions

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

React Nanodegree Aug 2018
Front End Dev Nanodegree Jul 2018
Full Stack Dev Nanodegree May 2018
Android Basics Nanodegree Apr 2018
FCC Front End Certificate Feb 2018

## **VOLUNTEER**

**Mew Cat Rescue** Feb 2019 - present Developer and Designer

**Mercy House** Aug 2014 - Oct 2017 Photographer

Girl Scouts of USA Aug 2010 - May 2012

Daisy and Brownie Leader

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer

May 2018 - present

Walmart - Bentonville, AR

- Lead Frontend Developer of nine person team building custom ERP system integrating with legacy and third party services saving company \$1 million in operating costs in Q1 2019 alone.
- Lead Developer and Systems Architect for React UI Library suite encompassing designs for structural, presentational, chatbot and feedback components with dynamically rendered web documentation.
- Support other teams' development projects as needed. I.e. project architecture mapping, specific feature development and application optimization.ping, specific feature development and application optimization.
- Mentoring junior developers with 1:1 React/React Native teaching sessions and career/ goal planning.

# Mobile and Web Application Developer

Sept 2018 - present

Tabbert Technologies, LLC - Bentonville, AR

- Partnering with nonprofits and local businesses to create websites and mobile applications using WordPress (JS/PHP), ReactJS, React Native and Native Android.
- Focusing on reaching customers, donors, and recipients using modern UI/UX principles and SEO optimization for maximum reach.

#### Frontend Developer (Remote)

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018

Chingu - Toronto, Canada

- Front end development of the original Chingu Developer Network client using React and interfacing with a Node/GraphQL/PostgreSQL backend.
- Facilitate 8-10 week long Voyage cohorts of 350 persons across 75 nations.

# **PROJECTS**

Chingu.io: Front end development of the Chingu Development Network client using React and interfacing with a Node/GraphQL/PostgreSQL backend.

<u>Designsteins</u>: Design company custom WordPress theme built witth php and JavaScript.

<u>IAmSoGal</u>: Flexible WordPress custom theme for international venture capital firm.

ModMemes: Meme Library web application using MERN stack.

<u>TuVotoTuIdioma</u>: WordPress based informational site for a non-profit, All Voting Is Local, using php, jQuery and HTML5/CSS3.

JuniperMail: Survey generation site using MERN stack with Stripe and Sendgrid.

Bearbnb: Clone of Airbnb using ReactJS/Redux, Express, Node.js and MongoDB.

Vannya.me: Portfolio site using React where additional work can be found.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelors of Science, Software Development Western Governors University

Expected Sept 2020

Java, JavaScript, Mobile Apps, SQL, UI and UX.

Associates of Applied Science, Software Development Dec 2017

North Lake College - Irving, TX

Programming in Java and C++. President's Honor Roll. GPA 3.95

Programming in Java and C++. President's Honor Rott. GPA 3.95

Associates of Arts, Liberal Studies North Lake College - Irving, TX May 2017

Areas: Accounting, Calculus, Geology and Photography. GPA 3.92